What?
We…
Why are we here?
We evacuated here
because of the typhoon, right?
But who brought us all the way here?
What is this place?
-Where are we?
-Huh? What?
It's a shrine!
-A shrine?
-What?
Thank you for having us.
Huh?
Whoa! Look at this!
What?
A large-scale landslide
has occurred in Tatsumi Town.
Many local houses
were caught up in the landslide,
but there have been no casualties.
-Is this where the villa was?
-Yeah.
The villa is gone!
The road is over there,
so the villa was completely washed away!
-This is the orange garden!
-You're right!
Wait a minute.
If we had stayed there,
we would have died.
Yeah. If we hadn't left the villa
back then, by now, we would be…
Hey!
My grandma's ashes!
-Grandma, the villa is gone!
-Grandma…
They brought her…
Is God telling us
that our vacation is over?
God?
What kind of god
would cause a disaster like this?
True.
Yeah, no god or Buddha
would do something like this!
What kind of god helped us…
Everyone, let's calm down!
Come on. It's a shame that the villa
is gone, but we all survived!
The land remains.
I will make it big as an actor…
I'll rebuild
a Konta villa there in no time!
Then we can all have a barbecue again!
-Konta!
-Oh, Rinrin!
Oh, sorry, Rinrin!
TWO DAYS LATER
Well, our vacation was forced to an end.
Shall we get to work?
No other choice…
Everyone has to work after all.
You can't survive without money.
My savings ran out,
so I'll get a part-time job.
I should also register
at a new temp agency.
I need to find a new job.
I will work too.
Well, our long summer vacation is over.
Do your best with the movie.
Yeah, leave it to me.
I'll do my best.
Come on, everyone!
-What?
-Back to society! Let's go!
Be quiet! You're bothering
the other customers.
-I'm sorry.
-Cut it out!
Tetsuro. Stop paying with cash.
-Here, use this to pay.
-Got it.
See you all!
-See you.
-I'll send you the money!
-Okay.
-Bye, Midori. See you later!
-See you!
-I'll be in touch, Konta.
Please!
She's too cute.
Excuse me!
Dad? Hello, what's wrong?
Disaster insurance?
Oh, right.
You're going to the government office
to do the paperwork?
I see.
Okay, thank you.
For now,
I'll take Grandma's urn to my place.
Yeah.
Okay.
Dad, I'm here too!
Sorry, I hung up.
Never mind.
Oh, it's my manager.
Hello?
Yes, I've been well.
Oh, yes. I'm in Tokyo right now.
Huh? Seriously?
Yes, I'll be there.
I'll head over right now. Yes, okay.
I understand.
I'll do my best. Excuse me.
-Oh, man.
-Huh?
I got a role. A late-night drama.
And I have lines!
Oh, that's great!
As I thought, Tokyo was waiting for me.
Well, I'm off. They're already shooting.
-Take care.
-All right. Um…
As for the money, Midori, you pay.
Thank you!
Why is this spot empty?
I need to move forward too.
Thank you very much.
ORANGE PEELS 500 YEN
These too, please.
Certainly.
You've done something terrible.
I'm sorry.
I erased those humans' memories.
No one remembers you anymore.
Your human form has become grains of sand,
turned into sea foam,
and vanished.
However!
The Dragon God
has headhunted you.
What?
Japan is a land of gods.
And the shrines that have existed there
since ancient times
operate on different values
compared to us.
My reason for existing
was to witness the demise of humans.
To see them delivered to the underworld.
But…
I lost sight of my duties as Grim Reaper.
And ended up saving their lives.
Why did it come to this?
It was an unprecedented act of misconduct.
Why did you have to cause such trouble?
I want to know the reason.
Why?
Because I was on vacation.
I've often been told that vacations
change a person's way of thinking.
But to think it would
even affect a Grim Reaper…
Well…
As a result, for better or worse,
that god, the Dragon, has recruited you.
Those gods over there, unlike us,
have been helping humans
since ancient times.
It's like their main job.
Even a soft-hearted, good-for-nothing
Grim Reaper like you
might have some potential,
from their point of view.
You are the man they need…
No,
the god they need.
Something like that.
So…
If I become a god of a shrine,
are you going to revive me again?
Don't get ahead of yourself.
You won't become a god right away.
First, you must do decades
of community service.
No, in this case, earthly service.
You will reflect on your transgression,
while working in their world.
You only get one shot.
There are no redos.
If you hit the sea, that's where you go.
Nice throw.
Some fine control right there.
-Midori.
-Yes?
Do you want some coffee?
Oh, not right now.
Okay.
Hello, Konta?
How is the shoot going?
Period dramas must be tough, huh?
It's about the Great Tenpo famine,
so it seems I have to lose weight.
The director banned me from having lunch.
So…
I'm eating leaves for real!
In order to survive…
you even have to eat grass!
THE GREAT TENPO FAMINE
SHOOTING IS GOING SMOOTHLY!
Also, Rinrin is like,
incredibly busy with work.
We can't really meet up.
I see.
Both of you are working so hard,
it's admirable.
Admirable?
Wait, what about you, Midori?
What have you been up to?
Me?
Well, I…
There you go.
Summer oranges!
Konta.
Konta, do your best!
Until you make it big, I will work too!
In order to rebuild that villa,
you must become famous!
Yeah!
Rinrin, I'll do my best.
For your sake, and to rebuild that villa,
I'll risk my life to play this role!
Oh, sorry. Are you rolling? Sorry.
Oh, it's not a private call.
A utility company called.
Sorry, I'm so sorry.
I got scolded! I did!
Sorry, I'm sorry.
ONE YEAR LATER
It has been a year
since that vacation at the villa,
and the environment surrounding us
has changed a lot.
My brother is finally starting to be
recognized as an actor,
and little by little,
work has started coming in.
The man with the slicked-back hair
in Yama-chan,
played by Konta Hoshino, is coming in!
Shall I slick your hair back?
-Good morning.
-Morning.
Rinrin is still working
at the supermarket.
-Oh, Manager.
-Good morning.
-Do your best today.
I will!
Tsumugi started a part-time gig
doing tarot readings at a theme park.
Seems she got pretty good reviews,
so she's been doing this six days a week.
The tarot will reveal
all about your destiny!
Here goes!
You are not suited for business.
Give it up.
Seriously?
Tetsuro rarely contacts us,
but it seems he is working
at a campsite with a fishing pond.
By the way, Tetsuro also came up
with the title of the essay I am writing.
TAKING APPLICATIONS!
BIANNUAL ESSAY CONTEST
As you can see,
I started writing an illustrated essay.
I'm using that summer as material.
I wanted to leave a record
of the orange recipes from that villa.
Not as a smartphone video,
or a social media post,
but with my own hands.
As a kid, I drew terrible manga.
I haven't improved much since then,
but I feel like if I don't draw it,
I won't be able to move on.
I wish I had taken a picture of that sea.
A swallowtail butterfly.
Hey!
You dropped this.
A large summer orange.
You… can have it.
What?
Hello, Ms. Midori.
Hey.
Is there anywhere nice around here?
I came here to have a vacation.
Vacation…
THE VACATION PRINCIPLE
MY SUMMER ORANGE RECIPES
BY MIDORI HOSHINO
A VACATION FOR LIFE
Subtitle translation by: Nix S.